<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Salt Lake City's Best Real Estate Training</title>
    <description>Justin Udy, a top Real Estate Agent in Salt Lake City, shares his own internal real estate agent training for free. His Real Estate Training, Tips and Advice will help you sell more homes in less time.</description>
    <link>http://localhost:4000/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Thu, 05 Sep 2019 10:13:59 -0500</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 05 Sep 2019 10:13:59 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.7.3</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>5 Core Aspects of a Real Estate Career to Focus On</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/4hpaNUk0Jgc?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the hardest challenges I ever ran into as a brand-new agent was that I was only paying attention to getting more business, closing deals, making money, and moving onto the next transaction.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;To build a true business, I should have been focusing on the five core aspects of the real estate industry:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. Lead generation.&lt;/strong&gt; Schedule activities in your calendar that will build your business every day, including meeting new people, networking, and doing more to put your brand in front of people.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. Lead nurturing.&lt;/strong&gt; How do you nurture your leads? Do you use a notecard system, or do you have a CRM? Having an organized system is critical, especially if you have more leads coming in than you can handle on your own.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Did you know that it ends up costing a company almost five times as much to get a new lead than it does to keep one you already have?%20http://localhost:4000/5-core-aspects-of-a-real-estate-career-to-focus-on.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Did you know that it ends up costing a company almost five times as much to get a new lead than it does to keep one you already have?”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. Conversion.&lt;/strong&gt; Once you have leads coming in and you’re nurturing them, make sure that you’re providing them with something of value that will help them get to the next step in their goals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4. Delivery.&lt;/strong&gt; Make sure you follow through with the service professionally and efficiently; this involves just understanding our craft. You need to understand the “sticks and bricks” of a home, attend home inspections, and know how to negotiate in order to not only deliver the best product, but also world-class customer service.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;5. Retention.&lt;/strong&gt; This is one of the biggest aspects of real estate to focus on. Did you know that it ends up costing a company almost five times as much to get a new lead than it does to keep one you already have? Don’t just help your client the one time; make sure they know you’ll help them with all their current and future real estate needs. Have a campaign, system, or process in place to reach out to past clients, be it a quarterly newsletter, a monthly call, a client event, or whatever else you can do to stay in touch with them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re looking for options to help your team function better and run your business like a business, please feel free to reach out to me. I’m happy to discuss tactics and strategies with you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a final note: If you’re interested in becoming a member of a team—our team—reach out to us for an interview. We would love to speak with you about joining us. Either way, I wish you success in your career!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 29 Aug 2019 16:48:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/5-core-aspects-of-a-real-estate-career-to-focus-on.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/5-core-aspects-of-a-real-estate-career-to-focus-on.html</guid>
        
        <category>Lead Generation</category>
        
        <category>Lead Conversion</category>
        
        <category>Transaction Management</category>
        
        <category>Buyer Prospects</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Top 3 Books Every Agent Should Read</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/wXjqaZCHp9k?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As the saying goes, “Knowledge is power,” and what better way is there to learn than by reading? Today I’d like to share three incredible books that have definitely shaped the way I approach my life and my career. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. “Think and Grow Rich” by Napoleon Hill.&lt;/strong&gt; This is my go-to book to give as a gift every time someone in my life has a child graduating from college, high school, or even middle school. It’s just that powerful. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Despite what the word “rich” being in the title might make you think, this book isn’t just about how to build financial wealth. Its lessons also teach readers how to become “rich” mentally. The main thing to take away from this book is the importance of being optimistic and productive. Having a positive outlook, while still being proactive in making good things happen, is essential to “thinking and growing rich.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=To be a successful agent, you must find your niche and stick to it.%20http://localhost:4000/the-top-3-books-every-agent-should-read.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“To be a successful agent, you must find your niche and stick to it.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. “Why Now Is the Time to Crush It! Cash in on Your Passion” by Gary Vaynerchuk.&lt;/strong&gt; This book, which I got my hands on years ago when it was first published, has continued to be one of the most impactful books I’ve ever read. It taught me how to effectively operate in my market without having a huge budget to work off of. I learned the importance of consistent prospecting—something that’s still crucial to my business today. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. “The E Myth” by Michael E. Gerber.&lt;/strong&gt; Agents work themselves to the bone trying to earn their keep through commissions. All too often, this involves wearing more “hats” than we can handle. The reality is that to run a successful business, you need different people filling different, specific roles. Finding your niche and sticking to it is essential. Beyond that, you need to collaborate with other people who can fill the other necessary roles a real estate business must have to function. It was only after I did this, myself, that my production started increasing exponentially. Now, my team and I do hundreds of transactions each year. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even by reading just 10 pages a day, you can consume more than 20 books every single year. And I promise you that the more you read, the more you’ll grow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any other questions or would like more information about any of these books, feel free to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 15 Aug 2019 16:05:13 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/the-top-3-books-every-agent-should-read.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/the-top-3-books-every-agent-should-read.html</guid>
        
        <category>Transaction Management</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Are Bad Clients Causing Your Business To Stall?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/t5AcEdaW7Wo?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When it comes to having a profitable real estate career, choosing the right clients is as important as any other step you can take. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To illustrate this, I like to use the example of one of my son’s baseball games. He was seven at the time and kept swinging at pitches that were, to put it gently, not the best. I remember encouraging him later to not swing at those pitches, and, thinking about it now, that’s exactly the point I’m trying to make today.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Fellow agents: It’s time to stop swinging at bad pitches.&lt;/strong&gt; Just because an opportunity comes your way, that doesn’t mean you need to pursue it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But what if you don’t have the time or expertise to be selective about your clients? What if you don’t have enough leads in your pipeline?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well, ultimately, it’s best to realize that even in those circumstances, wasting your time on bad clients will only harm you in the long run. That time could be better spent on developing your skills and padding out your pipeline so that you can afford to be selective. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=When you make running a good business a priority, you’ll attract good people and good opportunities.%20http://localhost:4000/are-bad-clients-causing-your-business-to-stall.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“When you make running a good business a priority, you’ll attract good people and good opportunities.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Channeling your time and energy into positive opportunities and people will always be a better choice than the alternative.&lt;/strong&gt; While I generally believe people are good at their core, there are unfortunately some emotional vampires out there who drain your energy, your resources, and your emotional wellbeing. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So not only can bad clients be detrimental from a business perspective, they can be harmful on a personal level, as well. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thankfully, you have the control to avoid these kinds of people in your real estate career. Remember: What you do today will impact what happens to you three months down the line. In other words, make every moment of every day count. Your future self will be grateful for it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;At the end of the day, so long as your pipeline is full (which on my team means having at least 16 people in it), and your practices are sound, you and your business will be in good shape.&lt;/strong&gt; Not only that, but when you make running a good business a priority, you’ll attract good people and good opportunities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any other questions or would like more information, feel free to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 18 Jul 2019 14:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/are-bad-clients-causing-your-business-to-stall.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/are-bad-clients-causing-your-business-to-stall.html</guid>
        
        <category>Buyer Prospects</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The True Power of Database Marketing</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/U-Qk1Tbhz8E?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although a surprising number of agents don’t discuss or use database marketing in their business, it’s such an instrumental part of your success in this business. I made the same mistake when I got my start. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I once closed 97 transactions in a single year, and without an effective database marketing strategy in place, I would have been stretched much too thin to keep in touch with each and every client in my database. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On my team, &lt;strong&gt;our clients are our top source for both referrals and business, and achieving that with such success is only possible by staying in touch with our clients in a systematic and consistent manner.&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are a few techniques you can integrate into your business to sharpen your database marketing that I’ll go into today. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first technique is to &lt;strong&gt;call everyone in your database at least once every quarter.&lt;/strong&gt; If you’ve neglected to do this up until now, give them a call and reestablish a connection with them. Let them know that you’re sorry you haven’t been in touch and that you’re there if they need anything. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In addition to this, we &lt;strong&gt;send out two educational video messages each month&lt;/strong&gt; to demonstrate the breadth of our knowledge and expertise, which gives them confidence that we’ll help them reach their real estate goals. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Consider organizing client appreciation events.&lt;/strong&gt; Just recently, my team and I recorded a video that we’ll use to alert clients to an upcoming movie event we’re holding. We’ll host another around Thanksgiving time and then again next March. As a pro tip, schedule them in such a way that they’re three or four months apart. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=85% of agents are out of the business in their first five years, so people want to know they can place their trust in your hands with regard to their biggest asset.%20http://localhost:4000/the-true-power-of-database-marketing.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“85% of agents are out of the business in their first five years, so people want to know they can place their trust in your hands with regard to their biggest asset.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another thing that will prove to be beneficial is to &lt;strong&gt;construct and send out a newsletter to everyone in your database.&lt;/strong&gt; For our part, my team and I have been sending one out every quarter, but are planning to increase the frequency to every month or every two months. Doing this allows you to position yourself as an authority and provides something tangible that your clients can associate you with.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Because all these strategies and systems require some form of planning, they’ll be on your calendar, which will allow you to &lt;strong&gt;stay task-oriented and top of mind with the clients who make up your database.&lt;/strong&gt; Not only that, but showing consistency also sends the message that you’re an established professional. The message doesn’t have to be all real estate all the time, either: Calling them personally and extending an invite to coffee or stopping by a client’s home to deliver cookies for their birthday works just as well. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One point that bears repeating is that &lt;strong&gt;your clients need to see that you’re consistent.&lt;/strong&gt; As soon as you start to make great strides in your business, it’s easy to slack in this department, but clients need to know you’re here to stay. 85% of agents are out of the business in their first five years, so people want to know they can place their trust in your hands with regard to their biggest asset.   &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions whatsoever or there’s a topic you’d like to discuss, please don’t hesitate to reach out to us. We’d love to have a conversation with you! &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 07 Jun 2019 10:21:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/the-true-power-of-database-marketing.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/the-true-power-of-database-marketing.html</guid>
        
        <category>Lead Generation</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Join Me at My Upcoming Agent Training Event</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/jP5GRcMTmVM?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today I wanted to bring you an exciting announcement: On June 6th, I’m going to be hosting a training seminar on the top 10 things a brand-new agent should do. Even if you aren’t exactly brand-new, this class is still a great learning opportunity for any agents who aren’t selling at least 20 homes a year. Space for this class is limited, though, so be sure to &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eventbrite.com/e/real-estate-agent-training-presented-by-justin-udy-tickets-62376855855&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;RSVP here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; if you plan on attending. The event will take place in the ALV Mortgage office (7390 Creek Road Suite 201, Sandy, UT) and will run from 11:00 AM to 1:00PM. If you have any other questions or would like more information, feel free to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to seeing you on June 6th.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 29 May 2019 09:54:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/join-me-at-my-upcoming-agent-training-event.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/join-me-at-my-upcoming-agent-training-event.html</guid>
        
        <category>Transaction Management</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>3 Critical Activities to be a Top Producer</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/2LwzmUOMakM?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s a statistic for you: 87% of real estate agents will be out of the industry within their first five years on the job. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In order to continue fueling your own success so that your career in real estate doesn’t suffer the same fate, consider and avoid these three common reasons for failure: &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. Those who fail are not committed.&lt;/strong&gt; Unfortunately, many enter this career with misguided expectations—business will come knocking on their door and the phone will ring off the hook from the moment they begin. We as committed professionals know that this is a lead-generating business, which is why establishing a prospecting schedule is imperative. Those who’ve demonstrated a commitment to this business know that their time should be devoted to prospecting, lead generating, attending appointments, and negotiating deals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Those who’ve demonstrated a commitment to this business know that their time should be devoted to prospecting, lead generating, attending appointments, and negotiating deals.%20http://localhost:4000/3-critical-activities-to-be-a-top-producer.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Those who’ve demonstrated a commitment to this business know that their time should be devoted to prospecting, lead generating, attending appointments, and negotiating deals.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. They can’t sell homes.&lt;/strong&gt; I’ve met quite a few people who possess the gift of gab, but their shortcomings are in their sales skills. This is a script-and-dialogue business, and it’s our job to effectively communicate with our clients, lead them, and lay out all their options. This means we need to understand scripts and tonality when helping clients reach a well-informed, maximally beneficial decision. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. They quit after a few bad experiences.&lt;/strong&gt; Rejection in this business is something we’re all accustomed to. It becomes problematic when the agent internalizes this experience and it weighs on their ability to move forward and maintain the attitude that they’re going to create more business. This self-doubt and insecurity tends to lead to excuses, and it spills over into other facets of their life; sadly, this only compounds the issue further.   &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Don’t let yourself fall into the psychological loop of “can’t.” I can’t tell you how many agents I’ve met with that suffer from being in their own heads. As you press on and begin to do more business, you’ll realize that you’re only one deal away from getting your mindset right. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have questions or need help with your business in any way, please reach out to me. I hope to speak with you soon!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 28 Mar 2019 12:03:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/3-critical-activities-to-be-a-top-producer.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/3-critical-activities-to-be-a-top-producer.html</guid>
        
        <category>Transaction Management</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Role of Prospecting in a Changing Market</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/loh3Kb4KXOE?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m excited to bring you my latest message on what to do in a changing market. If you haven’t already, be sure to &lt;a href=&quot;https://utahrealestatetraining.com/prepare-yourself-for-our-2019-market.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;check out my earlier videos&lt;/a&gt; on the topic.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Being prepared for changes our market will continue to endure is a must in the world of real estate. As many as 85% of agents are out of the business within their first five years, and that number shoots up to 98% for agents that make it 10 years.    &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;To avoid becoming part of the statistic, prospecting is integral to your success.&lt;/strong&gt; This is far from everyone’s favorite part of the job, but there’s a succinct phrase to consider: A closed mouth will never get fed. It’s a simple rule, but fundamentally important to remember. The only way you can grow your business and stay in business is through prospecting. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The market forecast for 2019 was clear—along with a rise in market prices, we will have fewer sales. Accounting for this, you’ll need to make the most of your opportunities and employ the most effective strategies. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=There’s a succinct phrase to consider: A closed mouth will never get fed.%20http://localhost:4000/the-role-of-prospecting-in-a-changing-market.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“There’s a succinct phrase to consider: A closed mouth will never get fed.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Organize the business you’ll acquire into these three categories: &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Today business.&lt;/strong&gt; These are prospects that have to act with immediacy, and they include For Sale By Owner (FSBOs), sellers that have a short window of time to move, etc.    &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tomorrow business.&lt;/strong&gt; This is your follow-up business, or those who aren’t ready to act just yet but will be relatively soon. This includes those with a lease that’s nearing its end or those who are a month or so away from getting into the market.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Passive business.&lt;/strong&gt; This mode of business is centered around your consistent outreach and will come from your friends, family, and others close to you.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;On top of that, you need to make it your mission to master five facets of your prospecting, effectively becoming a specialist in those areas;&lt;/strong&gt; examples are calling FSBOs unrelentingly, mailing people in your sphere of influence each and every month, and door knocking at least once a week, just to name a few.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Set daily standards for the number of contacts we make a day and compare those markers with last year’s standards.&lt;/strong&gt; By doing this, you can pinpoint your No. 1 income-opportunity source from the prior year, capitalize on that source further, and leave room to supplement your strategy with other sources as well. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lastly, cast aside past behaviors and focus on a mentality that will drive your success now and that you can carry into the future.&lt;/strong&gt; The best time to get ahold of people is in the morning and Thursday afternoon, so if you don’t succeed at one of those times, try the other. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’d like more information, want a free business assessment, or have suggestions for a future video topic, please reach out to me. I hope to talk to you soon!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 05 Mar 2019 13:33:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/the-role-of-prospecting-in-a-changing-market.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/the-role-of-prospecting-in-a-changing-market.html</guid>
        
        <category>Buyer Prospects</category>
        
        <category>Lead Generation</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Agents: Make 2019 Your Best</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/qBFpnqvVZbQ?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even though the market is changing, there’s a lot you can do to make 2019 your best year yet. The housing forecast shows the market will likely go up in price but have fewer sales, and on top of this, there will be an influx of new agents this year. &lt;strong&gt;This means you’ll need to do something different.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When the market shifted, I dug deep and educated myself on the finer details of real estate. I flew to Chicago to learn more about financing, and that year I did 11 seller-financed deals in a market where closings just weren’t happening. &lt;strong&gt;We have to be educated, and we have to be masters of conversion.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=People don’t remember the home you got them into—they remember the experience you provided.%20http://localhost:4000/agents-make-2019-your-best.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“People don’t remember the home you got them into—they remember the experience you provided.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nobody wants to go with you unless they feel safe with you, &lt;strong&gt;so here are a few ways to position yourself as a leader and as a trustworthy professional:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. Have a great greeting and reach out at a high level.&lt;/strong&gt; You don’t want to come across badly in your first impression, so you need to really nail your phone greetings and interactions. I wear a suit not because I like it, but because it makes me look professional. In addition to acting professional, go the extra mile and learn about each client’s situation, so you can answer any questions they may have.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. Have a compelling argument as to how you run your business.&lt;/strong&gt; This is where your expertise comes into play—they’ve met you, and now they want to know if you’re a good fit. If you’re new to the business, make sure you’re educating yourself about the market and are reaching out to seasoned professionals for guidance. Their years of experience will help you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. Provide an amazing customer service experience.&lt;/strong&gt; Too many agents see their career as a paycheck instead of as a way to help families. You need to raise your standards and level of service in order for them to refer you, come back, and continue doing business with you. People don’t remember the home you got them into—they remember the experience you provided.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you do these three things while conducting your business, &lt;strong&gt;I guarantee you’ll have more sales, more clients, and your best year ever.&lt;/strong&gt; If you have any questions or need further information, feel free to reach out. I look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 15 Feb 2019 15:53:29 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/agents-make-2019-your-best.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/agents-make-2019-your-best.html</guid>
        
        <category>Transaction Management</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Do More With Less in 2019</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/EaOlpU4-2HI?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The market is changing in 2019, which means you have to find ways to do more with less in your business. How, though? There are a few things you can consider doing. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you prospect every day, for instance, your list of lead sources tends to shrink in a changing market. &lt;strong&gt;Since you’re spending more time with each contact, try getting creative with the ways you connect with these people.&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have a home showing scheduled at the end of the day, rather than just showing that home to a client, bring your business cards and try to do some door knocking in that area.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Doing more with less also includes your expenses, so get rid of any expenses you don’t need.%20http://localhost:4000/do-more-with-less-in-2019.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Doing more with less also includes your expenses, so get rid of any expenses you don’t need.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re preparing to publish a Facebook ad, redistribute the content you’re going to use for it on other social media platforms as well. In other words, repurpose that information. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, don’t forget that doing more with less also includes your expenses, so get rid of any expenses you don’t need. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Odds are you’ve never experienced a changing market, so I want to share another important message with you: It’s not scary. On the contrary, it’s a great opportunity for you to help many more people. The agents who don’t offer a high level of service in our industry tend to fade away. &lt;strong&gt;If you offer a world-class experience for your clients, though, you’re truly doing more with less, and that’s what will lead you to more business. &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As always, if you have any questions about this topic or you have another topic in mind you’d like to see me address in a future video, feel free to give me a call. I’d love to speak with you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 24 Jan 2019 12:19:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/do-more-with-less-in-2019.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/do-more-with-less-in-2019.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Prepare Yourself for Our 2019 Market</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/7s7z07qbkUQ?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What should you expect from our housing cycle in 2019?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many of you weren’t around when the market shifted back in 2008, but I was. At the time, I was worried and I wasn’t sure where my livelihood would go. There are a few things I wish I would’ve known then that I want to share with you now.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Take a look at what’s happening with our housing cycle right now. Each cycle lasts from seven to 10 years, and if you look at the market in general, interest rates, home prices, and inventory levels are rising. Once this happens, builders start making adjustments. In fact, a lot of builders are getting more and more hesitant to build homes over $500,000. When we start seeing these trends, we know there’s a bigger change happening. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m sure you’ve noticed this change. Some people think this means we’re in for a crazy spring, and hopefully that’s true. In the meantime, though, we know our market is changing, and we have to be prepared for it. What can you do to prepare yourself?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=When we start seeing these changes, we know there’s a bigger change happening.%20http://localhost:4000/prepare-yourself-for-our-2019-market.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“When we start seeing these changes, we know there’s a bigger change happening.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, &lt;strong&gt;make sure you have the right mindset and are motivated to work every single day.&lt;/strong&gt; It’s been easy these past few years to kick your feet up and let business come to you, but that won’t be that case anymore. Get your hands on as much motivational, self-help literature as you can and make sure you’re reading at least 10 pages a day. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Second, &lt;strong&gt;surround yourself with podcasts and other things that are positive in your mind.&lt;/strong&gt; This will help your business move forward. You might have to deal with a few breakdowns, but without breakdowns, there are no breakthroughs. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, &lt;strong&gt;take care of yourself.&lt;/strong&gt; Make sure you’re eating better and thinking better. If you increase productivity by 10% in 10 areas of your life, you increase by 100%. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Moving forward, I’ll be sharing more tips that I’ve learned in all my years in the business that will help you prepare for the future and keep your business moving forward.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions or there’s anything I can help you with in the meantime, don’t hesitate to reach out to me. I’d love to help you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 08 Jan 2019 12:23:16 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/prepare-yourself-for-our-2019-market.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/prepare-yourself-for-our-2019-market.html</guid>
        
        <category>Transaction Management</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
